《反恐24小时》前情提要
Previously on 24
杰克
Jack!
叫医护人员来
We need a medic!
生化剂比我们想的要厉害得多
The bioagent is more virulent than we thought.
我们所做的
All we're doing here is just
-只是掩蔽症状而已  -我明白
- Masking the symptoms. - I understand.
不过有件事你也许会考虑一下
There's something you may want to consider.
什么事
What's that?
一种采用干细胞的可能疗法
A possible treatment using stem cells
需从基因匹配的捐赠者身上提取
From a genetically compatible donor.
我看过你的档案  你有个女儿
I saw your file, and it says you have a daughter.
我不想把我的女儿牵扯进来
I don't want my daughter involved in this.
爸
Daddy.
沃克探员告诉我还有希望
Agent Walker told me that there's a chance,
一线希望  我可能救得了你
A small chance that I could help you,
而你却不希望我救你
And you don't want me to.
我快死了
I'm dying,
即便有能让我幸存的一线生机
And whatever small chance there is to stop that from happening
我也不要冒着风险  让你坐在我身边
It is not worth the pain for me to let you
看我死去  那样太痛苦了
Sit there and watch me die.
杰克  霍奇斯持有13枚
Jack, hodges has 13 python missiles
载有生化武器的巨蟒导弹
Armed with the bioweapons.
他要求我召回战斗机
He demanded that i recall the planes,
否则就会发射导弹
Or he would launch.
托尼·阿尔梅达还在斯塔克伍德里面
Tony almeida is still inside Starkwood.
他认为自己能够进到燃料库
He believes he can gain access to the fuel depot,
放置连环炸药装置
And lay a series of explosive charges,
从而摧毁那些导弹
And take the missiles out.
你知道自己在做什么吗
What do you think you're doing?
带我去燃料罐那里
You're gonna take me down to the fuel tanks.
乔纳斯  你的导弹已经被我们摧毁了
Jonas, we've taken out your missiles.
你玩完了  你被捕了
It's over, and you're under arrest.
你将面对的  是你无法想象的对手
You can't even begin to imagine what you're up against.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
你会知道的
You'll find out.
莫斯探员  我是戴维斯  在6号侧门
Agent Moss, this is Davis at auxiliary gate 6.
我抓到了一个斯塔克伍德的人
I have a Starkwood op in custody.
他随身携带一罐生化武器
He was carrying a canister of the bioweapon.
-确定是生化武器吗  -就在我眼前
- Are you sure? - I'm looking at it right now.
斯塔克伍德的一个雇佣兵
One of the Starkwood ops
他带走了一罐生化武器
He's got a canister of the bioweapon.
所以我要你封锁所有出去的道路
So I need you to close down all access roads,
让周边小组和首府警察保持警戒
And alert perimeter units and metro police.
詹尼丝  给我接通首府警局
Janis, get me D.C. metro.
我将进行空中追捕
I'm gonna pursue from the air.
快走
Let's go!
快
Come on!
我没事
I'm okay.
托尼  托尼
Tony! Tony!
老天
Oh, god. oh...
以下情节发生在凌晨2点至3点间
The following takes place between 2 a.m. and 3 a.m.
帕特丽夏  我是马特
Patricia, Matt.
我刚跟特勤组通完电话
I just got off phone with secret service.
已在白宫南门入口安检处
You're cleared with white house
给你办了出入手续
Security at the south entrance.
你多久能到那里
How soon do you think you can get there?
有关于霍奇斯被拘捕的更多信息吗
Do you have any more information why Hodges was arrested?
他们没有透露太多
They didn't give me a lot.
明显的是  乔纳斯当时正跟总统
Apparently, Jonas was in some kind
进行某种政治会面
Of policy meeting with the president,
然后情况失控了
And things got out of hand.
接着他要求见他亲爱的律师
That's when he requested his favorite attorney.
荣幸之至
I'm flattered.
我跟他谈完再给你电话
I'll call you after I've spoken to him.
搞快点
Hurry it up.
詹尼斯  我们刚刚识别出了疑犯的身份
Janis, we just got an ID on the suspect.
斯塔克伍德的一台监控摄像机
One of Starkwood's security cameras
捕捉到了他离开基地的画面
Picked him up leaving the compound;
他当时拿着一个背包
He was carrying a backpack.
在斯塔克伍德工作过两年
Two-year Starkwood employee.
前特种部队成员
Former special forces.
把这信息传给拉里
Relay that information to Larry.
他需要知道我们追捕的对象
He needs to know who we are stalking,
我在用对讲机联系他  但他一直没回应
I've been trying. He's not answering his comm.
增援人员有多远
How far away is backup?
他们还有几分钟  帕克的小组
They're still a few minutes out, but agent Park's teams
已建立了四个街区的封锁线
Have secured a four-block perimeter.
装生化武器的罐子就在封锁区里
The bioweapons canister is secured within the cordon.
将盖尔维兹的图像及描述
Get Galvez' picture and description out
分发给战术小组及各部门
To tactical and distribute department wide.
好
Got it.
继续联系拉里
And keep trying Larry.
各小组注意
To all units,
我正将疑犯照片上传至
I'm uploading a photo of the suspect
各小组成员的掌上电脑上
To all units' PDAs.
疑犯名字是罗伯特·盖尔维兹
His name is Robert Galvez.
请注意
Be advised
疑犯受过强化军事训练
He has advanced military training,
各小组小心行动
So proceed with caution.
阿尔梅达  阿尔梅达  在吗
Almeida? Almeida, are you there?
你到安全位置了吗
Are you in a secure location?
我躲在杰弗逊大街
I'm holed up in a storage yard
建筑工程屋旁的堆场里
near the projects on Jefferson.
我刚看到一个巡逻警察
But I just spotted a patrol.
我最好离开这里
I think I better keep moving.
别走
No, don't.
调查局刚刚封锁了整个区域
The FBI's got the entire perimeter locked down.
他们知道你是谁
And they know who you are.
怎么知道的
How?
他们有你的图像
They have a picture.
所以搜捕队看见你就能认出来
Which means the search teams can ID you on sight.
待在原地  我看见他们的搜捕协议后
Just stay put until I can get a read
会引导你逃出去的
On their search protocols, and I'll guide you out.
我当初真不应该听你的来帮你
I should have never let you talk me into helping you.
我答应你  你帮我偷的那个罐子
I promise you, that canister you stole for me
我效力的那些人会付很多钱的
Is worth a lot of money to the people I'm working for.
我坐牢那些钱还有个屁用
Hell of a lot of good that money's gonna do me in prison.
闭嘴  照我说的做
Just shut up and do what I tell you to do.
守好罐子  原地待命  等我的电话
Guard the canister, stay put, and wait for my call.
有探员受伤
We've got agents down.
快派医疗队来
Get a med team out here now.
阿尔梅达
Almeida?
阿尔梅达  听得到吗
Almeida, can you hear me?
出什么事了
What happened?
疑犯在哪里
Where's the suspect?
他偷袭了我们
He ambushed us.
你看见他往哪边去了吗
Did you see where he went?
我不知道
I don't know.
蕾妮  我刚刚得到确认
Renee, I just got confirmation
战术小组已到达现场
The tac team has arrived at the scene.
-有拉里的消息吗  -还没有
- Do we have a 20 on Larry? - Not yet.
打扰一下  沃克探员
Excuse me, agent Walker.
-我知道你很忙  -金
- I know you're busy. - Kim.
我是来向你告别的
I just came to say good-bye.
告别  你要去哪里
Good-bye? Where are you going?
回洛杉矶
Back to L.A.
我不明白
Um, I don't understand.
你不打算进行实验疗法来救你父亲了吗
You're not going through with the treatment to help your father?
这是他治愈的唯一机会啊
I mean, it's his only chance for a cure.
我知道  他也知道
I know that, and so does he.
但机会渺茫
But it's a slim one,
他觉得
And he believes
不值得一试
It's not worth taking, so...
如果真的不幸发生  他希望独自承担
If he's going to die, he wants it to be on his terms.
对  但你不能让他回心转意吗
Yes, but can't you change his mind?
我觉得你现在应该会了解到
I would think you'd know by now
我爸爸一但下定决心
That no one can change my father's mind
没人可以改变
When it's made up.
我  我很抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry.
对不起我让你处在这种境地
I'm sorry that I put you in this position.
不要这么说
No,don't be.
我对你充满了感激  沃克探员
I'm grateful to you, agent walker.
我和我爸爸说了好多事情
My father and I got to say a lot of things to each other.
我真想能再和他多聊聊
I wish I could have said more,
但是我不想让他更加痛苦了
But i don't want to cause him any more pain.
蕾妮
Renee?
帕克探员找你
Agent park is on the phone for you.
我要接这个电话
I need to take this.
我明白
I understand.
祝你好运
Good luck.
沃克  请讲
This is walker.
莫斯探员牺牲了
Agent Moss is dead.
什么
What?
他中了嫌疑犯的埋伏
Apparently,he was killed in an ambush by the suspect.
直升机飞行员也死了
The chopper pilot,too.
托尼·阿尔梅达也中枪  但是还活着
Tony Almeida's been shot, but he's alive.
医务人员正在救治他
I've got medical personnel working on him now.
沃克探员
Agent Walker?
卡维兹有线索了吗
Do we have any lead on galvez?
还没  但是这片区域已经被我们重重封锁
No,but the area's been cordoned off.
他跑不了多远
He couldn't have gotten far.
我们在现场设立了一个行动基地
We're setting up an operations base here on the scene
配合搜捕
To coordinate the manhunt.
现在你要怎么处理
How do you want to proceed?
我
Me?
你现在是级别最高的探员了
You're the ranking agent in charge now.
保持封锁
Maintain the perimeter.
展开一次从南到北的地毯式搜捕
Begin a south-north sweep.
我会尽快带一个小组赶赴现场
I'll chopper out a team and meet you there as soon as I can.
沃克探员  我有足够的人力部署
Agent walker,iI have more than enough personnel.
-你不用亲自参加搜捕  -我必须要去
- You don't need to be involved in the search. - Yes,I do.
-有新情报随时通知我  -是的  长官
- Keep me posted if you hear anything. - Yes,ma'am.
拉里怎么样了
Larry?
他在与嫌疑犯交火时被枪杀
He was killed in a shootout with the suspect.
天哪
Oh,god.
你告知一下白宫
I need you to brief the white house on what's happened.
通知梅瑟尔医生在封锁线
Call dr. macer and have her deploy a hazmat team
附近部署一支危险品应急小队
To the perimeter line.
召集一个小组和我赶去现场
Assemble a team to chopper out with me.
我真的很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
必须有人去告知一下拉里的前妻
Someone's going to need to notify larry's ex-wife.
但不该由我去说
Probably shouldn't be me.
没事  我去告诉她好了
It's okay. I'll take care of it.
好
All right.
刚才我们回顾了3点到8点
We've debrifed on hours 8:am to 3:00 p.m.
关于回收CIP装置
Pertaining to the cip recovery
和抓获埃克·杜巴库的事
and the capture of Ike Dubaku
鲍尔先生
Now,Mr. Bauer,
你休息一下吧
Maybe you'd like to take a break.
不  应该在我还清醒的时候做完简报
No. we need to finish this while i still can.
继续
Let's go.
根据你之前的汇报说
Now,according to your earlier statement,
差不多这个时候
It was about this time you received
你收到白宫受到威胁的情报
Intel regarding the imminent attack on the white house.
是托尼·阿尔梅达提供给我的
Tony almeida provided me with the intel,
但我们当时并不知道
But we did not know
白宫是袭击目标
The white house was a target at that time.
谁是阿尔梅达的消息来源
And who was mr. almeida's source?
他是在审讯中从一个雇佣兵口中得知的
He was interrogating a mercenary.
他说名字了吗
Did almeida give you a name?
嗯
Um...
对不起
Yeah. sorry.
卡蒂夫  他说是文森特·卡蒂夫
Car... cardiff. he said his name was Vincent Cardiff.
你有没有亲自对他问询过
Did you yourself question the source?
没有
No.
他没有撑过托尼的拷问
He didn't survive tony's interrogation,
但是他告诉我们关于下一次袭击的情报
But he was the one who provided us with the intel on the upcoming attack.
但我们当时并不知道
But we did not know
白宫是袭击目标
That the white house was the intended target at that time.
我们当时并不知道白宫是袭击目标
We did not know the white house was the intended target...
鲍尔先生
Mr. Bauer?
你还坚持不要休息吗
You sure you don't want to take that break?
我又在不断重复了
Um,I'm repeating myself again.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这是你要的数据文件
Here's the data file you asked for,sir.
汤姆  快点
Tom,we need to move.
沃克探员给我们派了任务
Agent walker's got our assignments.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我们一定要控制局势
We're not going to lose control of this situation.
我知道你们都加了班  很累了
I know that most of you are tired,working double shifts,
但是我要你们全部精神集中且保持警惕
But I need each and every one of you focused and alert
我们要找到嫌犯
If we are going to locate the suspect
和他身上的生化武器罐
And secure the bioweapon canister that he's carrying.
我在执行外勤任务时
While I am out in the field,
相关情报都要交给詹尼斯
You will pass all pertinent information out of this office through Janis.
我们出发  亚当斯  你的队伍归我管
Let's get to work. Adams, you and your men are with me.
蕾妮  蕾妮
Renee? Renee?
我在直升机场等你
I'll meet you at the helipad.
生化武器还没有找到吗
The bioweapon's still out there?
局势在我们掌控中
We have it contained.
等会儿
Wait a second.
到底发生什么事了
Just tell me what the hell is going on.
一个斯塔克伍德雇佣兵罗伯特·卡维兹
A starkwood operative by the name of robert galvez
拿了一个病原体的毒气罐逃走了
Got away with a canister of the pathogen.
我们在斯塔克伍德基地
We have him trapped inside a perimeter a mile or so
附近已经包围了他
From starkwood's compound.
现场封锁归拉里管吗
Is larry in command of the perimeter?
他在交火时牺牲了
He was killed in a firefight.
什么
What?
托尼受伤了
Tony was injured.
他和先遣部队在现场
He's at the scene with the advance team.
拉里死了
Larry's dead?
两个探员牺牲了
We have two agents down.
我要走了
Yes. I have to go.
你很幸运  子弹再往左偏一寸
You're lucky. an inch to the left,
就会打到你的脾动脉了
The bullet might have nicked your splenic artery.
你应该再去医院检查一下
You need to get yourself checked out at the hospital,sir.
我知道  但现在不行
Yeah,I can't do that right now.
我给你点镇痛剂吧
Let me get you something for the pain.
不了  我要保持头脑清醒
No,I,I need to keep my head clear.
9号搜捕队   这里是移动指挥部
Sweep 9,this is mobile command,
什么情况
what's your status?
移动指挥部  这里是9号搜捕队
Mobile command,this is sweep 9,
东南方向211位置安全
southeast grid 211 clear.
- 继续前进  -收到  9号搜捕队
- Moving on. - Copy that,sweep 9.
7号搜捕队  什么情况
Sweep 7,what's your position?
214位置安全  没有发现嫌犯
Clearing 214. nothing so far.
没有他的踪迹吗
No sign of him?
别担心
Don't worry.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
你去休息一下吧
You should get some rest.
谢谢
Thanks.
这里是移动指挥部  通报情况
...this is mobile command, status check.
-喂  - 他们在北边
- Yeah? - yeah,they're sweeping
进行地毯式搜捕
North,clearing grids.
你从杰弗逊大街到12和13号街一路畅通
You've got a clear path on jefferson all the way up to 12th and 13th street.
那应是他们搜查的最后一个区域
That should be the last sector they're searching.
照他们的进展来看
Judging by their progress,
你有30分钟时间
It'll give you about 30 minutes.
时间足够了
Should be plenty of time.
足够做什么
Time for what?
我给你的C-4炸药还在吧
You still got that c-4 I gave you?
-对  在我这  -好
- Yeah. I got it. - All right.
你去找一幢大楼
I want you to find a structure,
商场  仓库之类足够大
A store, warehouse, something big enough
他们不得不进去搜查的地方
Where they have to enter and search.
我们要把他们
We need to draw as many of them
尽可能多地引进楼里
Into the building as possible.
然后引爆
Then blow it.
你要我灭掉那些调查局探员吗
You want me to blow up a couple of dozen FBI agents?
有什么问题吗
You got a problem with that?
他们还是会设置封锁线
They're still gonna have the perimeter locked down.
我可不认为这样做
I don't see how doing this
就能让我带着毒气罐离开
Is gonna get me out of here with the canister.
我已经想好对策了
Yeah, I've got that worked out.
杰克  你怎么来了
Jack, what the hell are you doing?
我和你一起去
I'm going with you.
你病了
You're ill.
如果我妨碍了你的行动
If my condition interferes with your operation,
我会退出
I will stand down.
-我保证  -杰克
- I give you my word. - Jack...
你要把时间都浪费在
You want keep arguing about this,
无意义的争论上吗  那好
Waste more time? fine.
我不会下去的
I'm not getting out.
早上好
Good morning.
埃姆斯女士
Ms. Eames.
你是乔纳斯·霍奇斯的律师
You're Jonas Hodges' attorney.
没错
That's right.
上头说你会来
They told us to expect you.
请把你的拇指
I just need you to place your thumb
放在玻璃上
Against the glass.
好了  卡登探员会送你
Okay. Sergeant Cadden will escort you
去等候区
To the holding area.
谢谢
Thank you.
这个人怎么会携带一罐生化武器
How could this man have gotten out of Starkwood
逃出斯塔克伍德的
With a canister of the bioweapon?
没人知道
No one's sure.
不过他已经杀了4个人
But he's already murdered four people.
包括拉里·莫斯
Including Larry Moss.
调查局追踪他
The FBI has tracked him
到了附近的一个居民区
To a nearby residential district.
他们封锁了整个区域
They've sealed off the area
正在展开地毯式搜查
And are conducting a thorough search.
妈  这个卡维兹在斯塔克伍德工作
Mom,this man Galvez is a Starkwood operative.
很明显  霍奇斯是幕后主谋
Clearly, Hodges is behind this.
或许吧
Maybe.
你说或许是什么意思
What do you mean, maybe?
霍奇斯被逮捕时
As hodges was taken away,
他说还没结束
He said it wasn't over.
他提到了还有其他人
He alluded to others,
说他自己只是冰山一角
Called himself a small cog in a very large machine
我没有能力去阻止他们
That I wouldn't be able to stop.
他在危言耸听
He was ranting.
他不一定是在说谎
That doesn't mean he wasn't telling the truth.
我们要查清楚霍奇斯到底知道些什么
We need to find out what Hodges knows about this.
把他带去调查局审问
I want him taken to the FBI for interrogation.
妈  他是反社会者
He's a sociopath, mom.
他不会交代的  他一定会
He's not going to talk. He's going to want
以合作为条件来跟你谈交易
To make some kind of deal in exchange for his cooperation.
妈  你不是想
Mom, you're not considering that...
奥利维亚
Olivia...
你了解这个人  知道他对罗杰做了什么
You know what this man is, what he did to roger.
把他带去调查局
Just get him to FBI.
霍奇斯先生
Mr. Hodges.
你的律师到了
Your attorney's here to see you.
在这个该死的时候
Well, it's about damn time.
我们想私下谈谈
We're going to need some privacy.
你比她高一点
You're a little taller than her.
但这样也挺漂亮
But it's a good look for you.
你好  乔纳斯
Hello, Jonas.
我不关心你是怎样进来的
I'm not going to ask how you got in.
我感兴趣的是你要如何把我弄出去
But i'm definitely interested in how you're going to get me out.
乔纳斯  你现在已是自身难保
Jonas, you're in a very difficult position.
你今天的所作所为
And your actions today have put everyone else
也让其他人寸步难行
In a very difficult position.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
我让他们不高兴了  对吧
I've upset the cart, have I?
每个人都很生气
Everyone's bent out of shape.
可是  政府冲着我公司发难时
Well, where the hell were they
他们又在哪里呢
When the government came after my company?
迈尔参议员和他的那群喽啰
When senator Mayer and his subpoena-waving goon squad
要毁掉我和我的心血时  他们在哪里
Were trying to ruin me and everything I've built?
我们本来可以提供保护的  乔纳斯
You would have been protected, Jonas.
保护你和斯塔克伍德
You and Starkwood.
但你差点毁了整个计划
But you jeopardized the plan.
你为我们研制的生化武器
That bioweapon that you developed for us was
不应用作私人用途
Not intended for personal use.
大家一致认为
The consensus
你有某种程度上的
Is that you've had some sort of...
精神崩溃
Psychotic break.
他们想错了
Well, the consensus is wrong.
现在听你说这句话  我们并不会感到安慰
Coming from you right now, that's not much comfort.
我要跟他们谈谈
I want to talk to them.
帮我联系一下
Get some form of communication between us.
我要跟他们谈谈
I want to talk to them.
为时已晚  乔纳斯
I think it's a little late for that, Jonas.
你的牌摊的太大了
You've brought undue attention by showing your hand.
暴露了你自己
Exposing yourself.
我知道你能理解
And I'm sure you could understand
他们觉得你或许会
Their concern that you may,
揭发其他人的顾虑
In fact, expose the others as well.
我能做到吗  我连他们是谁都不知道
How can I do that? I don't know who they are.
你知道的够多了  他们要确保没人透露
You know enough, and they need to be certain.
我想我们可以达成一致
I think we can agree
你的家人没有必要
That there's no reason for your family
为你的错误负责
To pay for your mistakes.
这就是你来的原因吗
Is that why you're here?
以我的家人威胁我
To threaten my family.
与此相反
On the contrary.
我来是要确保你家人的安全
I came to guarantee your family's safety.
如果你照我说的做
If you do the right thing.
这会让你心跳停止
It'll induce cardiac arrest,
而且不会留下痕迹
And leave no trace in your system.
自然地  有尊严地死去
A natural, dignified death.
到时他们无法对你进行起诉
Without you to prosecute,
这个针对你和你的公司的案子
The case against you and your
会很难继续  几乎不可能
Company will be difficult, likely impossible.
你这样做至少也是对
Preserving at least some small part
斯塔克伍德爱国传统的一些体现
Of starkwood's legacy of patriotic service.
我知道那对你来说很重要
Which I know is very important to you.
时间到了  律师
Party's over, counselor.
我们要把他转去调查局
We're moving him to the bureau.
我的委托人有权保持沉默
My client has invoked his right to silence and to counsel.
没我在场
No one speaks to him
谁都不能和他说话  明白吗
Unless in my presence, is that understood?
在一些国家他早就被枪毙了
In some countries they'd have shot him by now.
把他带走
Process him out.
请讲
Yes?
我见过他了
I met with him.
还有呢
And?
我确信他明白我们的意思
I'm quite certain he understands our terms.
他会被送到调查局接受审问
They're transferring him to the FBI for interrogation.
会有问题吗
Will that be a problem?
希望不会  那只会给他压力
Hopefully,it'll just pressure him
让他尽快下定决心
to resolve the situation sooner rather than later.
形势对我方有利后我就放宽心了
I'll be happy when this is behind us.
有阿尔梅达的消息吗
Have you heard from Almeida?
见到霍奇斯之前我接到了他的电话
He called in before I met with Hodges.
他拿到毒气罐了吗
Has he secured the canister?
很快
Soon.
他是你的人  最好别搞砸了
He's your guy. Better not screw this up.
托尼总是能力挽狂澜  转危为安
Tony's been the one bright spot in an otherwise dreary day.
我相信他能做好
I have faith he'll come through.
喂
Yeah?
我找到了一个安置点
I found a place to set up.
是一栋废弃的居民楼
It's an abandoned apartment building
距北边封锁线不远
just shy of the north perimeter line.
林孔街1297号  12大街的街角
1297 Rincon, corner of 12th.
好  我看到了
Yeah,I see it.
搜捕队刚刚进入
Sweep teams are just entering
南部的三个区
three sectors to the south.
你有不到20分钟
You've got less than 20 minutes.
时间不够啊
That doesn't give me much time.
是不够  所以你得
No,it doesn't, so maybe you
挂了电话赶紧干活儿
should get off the phone and get to it.
我曾连续失去过两个搭档
I lost two partners in a row.
早些时候
Early on.
我无能为力
I couldn't handle it.
我想这就是为什么在过去十年里
I guess that's why over the last ten years,
我一直是一个人单打独斗
I've pretty much worked alone.
去想这些悲伤的事情也没什么
It's all right for you to be feeling what you feel.
但你今晚不能这样消沉
And if you can't do this tonight,
也没什么
that's all right,too.
只是不要试着逞强
Just don't try and pretend
别装着自己什么感觉都没有
like you're not feeling anything.
要是那样就不对了
That's how you make a mistake.
拜托  杰克  不用教我该用什么感受
Please,Jack,don't tell me what to feel
或者如何调整心情
and don't tell me how to feel it.
沃克探员
Agent Walker.
他在那儿
He's over there.
-杰克  -他在哪
-Jack! -Where is he?
-他从这边跑了  -你还好吧
-He's running through this way. -You okay?
没事我很走运
Yeah,I got lucky.
子弹和要害部位擦肩而过
The bullet went straight through.
没想到在这儿会见到你
Didn't think I'd see you out here.
我来就是看看
I'm only here for observation.
你没必要这么做
You do not have to do this.
让我看
Show me.
盖上吧
Cover him up.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry about Larry.
这到底是怎么发生的
How the hell did this happen?
一切发生得都太快了  我是说
It all went down pretty fast,I mean...
我们还没下直升机就遭到伏击
We were ambushed before we got out of the helicopter.
驾驶员首先中弹
The chopper pilot was hit first.
我没带武器  拉里就掩护我
I was unarmed,so Larry laid down cover
我才得以逃生
so I could get clear.
我不记得太多  但的确有自动步枪的声音
I don't remember a lot,but I definitely heard auto-fire.
我被人追杀  拉里过来
As I was tagged, Larry came over
帮我  结果自己中弹
to help me out and that's when he was hit.
之后我就晕倒了
I blacked out after that.
但我确定是拉里救了我的命
But I'm pretty sure Larry saved my life.
拉里是被重武器打死的
Larry was hit with heavy ordnance.
身上有霰弹的碎片
Shotgun rounds,armor piercing.
你却明显是被小型武器击中的
You were obviously hit with something smaller.
我验过阿尔梅达先生的伤
I treated Mr. Almeida.
他的伤都是九毫米大
His wound was consistent with a nine millimeter.
你确定不是点四五口径
You sure it wasn't a .45?
不像  伤口太小  为什么这么问
Not likely-- the entry was too small. Why?
因为你们曾把点四五口径武器放在显眼处
Because you have spent .45 casings in evidence.
卡维兹能从调查局丢的车里搞到武器
Galvez had access to the weapons inside the FBI vehicle he stole here.
他可能会在火拼中换掉武器
He probably switched in the middle of the fight.
能换掉那么多
That many weapons?
你刚刚说的伏击时间很短啊
In the time frame that you described the ambush?
这可不合情理啊
It doesn't add up.
-好吧  那你的意思呢   -他有同党
- Okay,so what are you saying?  - Someone was with him.
我刚说了  一切发生得太快  但是
Like I said,it all happened pretty fast,but...
我是说  我不这么想
I mean,I didn't think so.
我觉得有道理
I guess it makes sense.
一个人做不到  他有帮手
One man didn't do this alone. He had help.
我去让帕克警戒这个区域
I'll tell Park to alert the field.
你确定你没事
You sure you're okay?
是  我很好
Yeah,I'm fine.
好
Good.
喂
Hello?
我吵醒你了吗
Did I wake you?
今天发这种事谁还睡得着
Who could sleep after what happened today?
你爸怎么样
How did it go with your father?
亲爱的  怎么了
Sweetheart,what is it?
怎么了
What happened?
他快死了  史蒂芬
He's dying,Stephen.
什么
What?
他被某种病毒感染了
He was exposed to something.
某种生化制剂
Like a biological agent.
和今天早些时候
It had something to do with the attacks
发生的袭击事件有关
that took place earlier today.
金  亲爱的  实在抱歉
Kim,honey,I'm so sorry.
还有治愈的希望吗
Um,isn't there anything that they can do?
没有
No.
我马上回家
I'm coming back home.
你不想留下吗  你不想
Don't you want to stay? Don't you wanna
尽可能多地陪他吗
be with him as long as you can?
我待在那儿
My presence,
他现在却受着苦
with what he's going through right now,
这只会让事情更糟
will only make things worse.
那你有没有告诉他
Did you at least,um,
告诉他  他有孙女了吗
Did you tell him about his granddaughter?
金
Kim?
我不能  史蒂芬
I couldn't,Stephen.
我不能告诉他
I couldn't bring myself to tell him
他不仅会扔下我一个
I wasn't the only person he was leaving behind.
跟他说泰瑞只会让事情更糟
Telling him about Teri would've only made it worse.
我会试着走610次航班  如果我赶上的话
I'm gonna trying get on the 610. If I do.
我九点就能到洛杉矶
I'll be back in L.A. by 9.
好
Okay.
要是改变注意了  就多留在那儿一会儿吧
You can always leave later, if you change your mind.
不会的
I won't.
我爱你们
I love you both.
我们也爱你
We love you,too.
再见
Bye.
移动指挥部  我是9号搜捕队
Mobile command,this is sweep 9.
221区域安全
221 is clear.
-继续搜索224区域  -收到
- Proceed to 224. - Copy that.
这个区域怎么没有被搜索
Why has that area of the grid not been cleared?
3号搜捕小队  你们怎么没搜219区
Sweep 3,why have you not cleared 219?
移动指挥部  我们遇到一些
Mobile command,we're encountering some resistance
社区内居民的阻挠
from neighborhood residents.
他们很不高兴  觉得不应该在凌晨两点半
They're not happy about their homes being searched
没有事先通知就搜查他们的房子
wIthout warning at 2:30 in the morning.
我在乎的是他们的安全  不是他们的心情
I'm concerned about their safety,not their happiness.
协助卡维兹的人可能会给他提供藏身之处
Whoever is helping Galvez may be providing him shelter
可能就是其中某间房屋  要是那些人
in one of those houses. If those civilians are
继续阻碍搜捕  先逮捕他们  再继续任务
interfering in that sweep, arrest them,but get that
明白吗
area cleared. Do you understand?
收到
Copy.
杰克
Jack?
失陪一下
Excuse me...
这是抗痉挛的药物
It's an antiseizure medicine.
我早就该用的
I should've used it earlier.
杰克  你在这干什么
Jack,what are you doing out here?
你为什么不呆在局里接受治疗
Why don't you go back to fbi medical and let them treat you?
没办法治
There is no treatment.
无药可医
There's no cure.
等下
Wait.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不知道
I didn't know.
你为什么来现场
Why are you in the field?
沃克探员的搭档刚刚牺牲了  托尼
Agent walker just lost her partner,Tony.
我觉得我能帮上忙  我欠她的
I thought I could help. I owe her that much.
斯托勒探员呼叫指挥中心  黄色代码
Agent stoller to mobile command. code yellow.
指挥中心  斯托勒探员请讲
Go ahead,agent Stoller, this is mobile command.
你是说黄色代码吗
Are you reporting a code yellow?
是的
Affirmative.
我看到了
I have a confirmed visual
身上有毒气罐
On the target suspect
的嫌犯
With the canister.
重复  我看到了
Repeat,confirmed visual
嫌犯和毒气罐
Of suspect and canister.
帕克探员  让我一下
Agent park,may I?
斯托勒探员  我是杰克·鲍尔
Agent stoller, this is jack bauer.
卡维兹有同伙吗
Is galvez with someone?
斯托勒探员
Agent stoller?
没  他一个人
Negative. he's alone.
收到
Copy that.
他在做什么
What's his 20?
他正在进入一个
Entering an abandoned apartment building
林孔街南边和12号街的交口处的
On the south side
废弃的公寓
Of rincon and 12th.
我在追击中
I am in pursuit.
别跟丢了  等待支援
Try to maintain a visual and wait for backup.
我们到达之前不要交火
Do not engage until we get there.
明白
Copy that.
所有分队向12号街和林孔路靠拢
All primary units respond to 12th and rincon.
发现嫌犯带着毒气罐
Suspect sighted entering
进入一座建筑
A building with canister.
-黄色代码  -帕克探员  把那栋楼围起来
- Code yellow. - Agent Park? I want a secure net
所有出口都要有岗哨
Around the building, agents at all exits and I want
阻击手把住四方
Sharpshooters covering each of the four exposures.
是的
Yes,ma'am.
杰克
Jack.
我不行
I can't.
没事的  我会好起来
It's all right,I'll be fine.
我就呆在这  我会监视行动的
I'll stay back, I'll watch operations.
你在那边小心点
You be careful out there.
我还是觉得卡维兹有搭档
I still think galvez has a partner.
你自己小心
You watch your back.
地狱之火
"hellfire."
你在巴基斯坦的27师服役过
You served with the 27th in Pakistan.
两次
Two tours,sir.
你有没有遇到斯塔克伍德的部队
Did you,by any chance, encounter any starkwood units?
有一个是由指挥官
There was a force protection team
调派给我们的保护分队
Attached by my c.o.
他们和你一起战斗
They fought with you.
是的
Yes,sir.
肩并肩的
Side by side.
士兵
Soldier
你怎么评价他们
How would you rate their professionalism?
在战火中的表现
Their performance under fire.
他们个个都是好手
They are good men, sir
受过良好的训练
Well trained.
多谢你
Thank you,son.
这是我今天最快乐的时刻
Just made my day.
我们出发
All right,let's go.
我们的命令是把囚犯
Our orders are to deliver the prisoner
从后门送入调查局
To the rear entrance at FBI.
白宫不希望声张此事
The white house wants to keep this low-key.
中士
Sarge!
我是肯登中士
This is sergeant Cadden.
犯人心脏病突发  呼吸困难
Prisoner's in severe cardiac and respiratory distress.
我们改变路线去
We are rerouting
西阿灵顿医院
To west arlington hospital.
准备好紧急医疗队
Need emergency medical team standing by!
快  出发
Go,go!
-集合队伍  -明白
- Assemble the teams. - You got it.
斯托勒探员  我是沃克探员  你收到吗
Agent stoller,this is agent Walker,do you copy?
收到  沃克探员
I copy you,agent walker.
你现在哪里
What is your position?
在东边一层到二层的楼梯间
East stairwell between the first and second floor.
嫌犯带着毒气罐
Suspect with canister
已经上了顶层
Has moved to the top floor.
有没有他有同伙的迹象
Do you have any indication that he's not alone?
没有  至少现在没有
Negative. not at this time.
好的  请待命  我们马上与你回合
All right,stand by. we're coming to you.
斯托勒探员说
Agent stoller puts the suspect
嫌犯在二楼某处
somewhere on the second floor
但是  有可能他
However,there's no guarantee
还有同伙
That he's the only hostile in the building.
因此  各位要严格按照程序一个个房间搜
Therefore,we stick to sop, clearing room by room.
帕克和我分别东边和西边各带一支分队
Agent park and I will lead two teams,east and west.
检查你们的武器和耳机
Check your weapons and headsets.
我们60秒后进入
We move in 60 seconds.
好  你们都听到了  跟我来
All right,you heard her, you guys are with me...
指挥中心  这是沃克
Mobile command,this is walker.
请讲  沃克探员
Go ahead,agent walker.
我们正要进入那栋建筑
We're about to enter the building.
让危险品处理小组准备好
Have hazmat teams on alert,in
以防毒气罐泄漏
case the canisteis have breached
收到
Copy that.
现在觉得如何
How you holding up?
好点  谢谢
Better,thanks.
对不起
Excuse me.
鲍尔  请讲
This is bauer.
鲍尔  这是米泽尔探员
Mr. bauer, this is agent mizelli.
很抱歉打扰你
Sorry to bother you with this,
但我想确定一下简报中的一个情报
But I need to follow up on something from our debrief.
探员  现在不是时候
Agent,this isn't a good time.
一些新的情报出现了
Some new information has come to light,and I need
-我要搞清楚一些矛盾的地方  -关于什么的
- To clear up a discrepancy.  - What discrepancy?
你告诉我说托尼·阿尔梅达关于白宫受袭击的情报
You told me tony almeida's source on the white house attack
是来自于文森特·卡蒂夫
Was a man identified to you as vincent cardiff?
是的
Yeah,that's right.
有没有可能你记错名字了
Is there a possibility you misremembered the name?
不  我不觉得
No,I don't think so.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你似乎听起来
You yourself have voiced some
不是很确定
Concern about your own acuity.
等下
Hold on.
这是什么
What is this here?
什么事先生
Sir?
米泽尔探员   我等会给你回话
Agent mizelli,I'm gonna have to get
这是所有人
Back to you. locator codes
的通讯发射器
For all units' radio transponders.
-是实时更新的吗  -是的
- Are they in real time?  - Yes,sir.
你能做下地图定位吗
Can you do a map overlay?
-需要一分钟  -去做
- It'll take a minute.  - get it done.
出什么事了  杰克
What's going on,jack?
我还不确定
I'm not sure yet.
好了吗  现在
Ready? now.
在这  这是斯托克的发射器
Right there,there's Stoller's transponder.
他都不在那栋楼里
He's not even in the building.
沃克探员  这是杰克
Agent walker,this is jack.
让你的人撤出那栋楼
Get your men out of the building.
-那是个陷井  -什么  杰克
- It's a trap.  - Jack,what?
斯托勒根本不在那  马上带你的人出去
Stoller's not even in there. get your men out now.
蓝色警报
Code blue.
沃克探员  帕克探员
Agent walker,agent park!
调辆车来给我
Get us a vehicle now!
各单位注意  我是帕克
All perimeter teams, this is Park.
多名探员受伤  我们在12号街和林孔街交口出
Agents are down. report to 12th and rincon.
我们需要帮助
We need assistance.
注意  注意  忽略刚才的命令
Negative,negative, disregard that order.
个单位原地待命
Maintain your positions.
重复  原地待命
I repeat,maintain your positions.
鲍尔  怎么回事
Bauer,what the hell are you doing?
他们目的是让我们的警戒线松动
They are trying to pull you off the line.
一但有警戒漏洞
You leave a hole in that perimeter,
毒气罐就会被偷运出去
We are going to lose the canister.
告诉你的人原地待命
Tell your men to stand fast.
医救队即将到达
Medivac is on its way.
让他们赶快过去
Get them in the air now!
杰克  我先进去了
Jack,I'm going in.
帕克探员
Agent Park.
-多少人失踪  -正在清点
- How many men are unaccounted for? - Still assessing.
爆炸的时候
There were at least 30 of us in the building
-我们至少有30人在大楼中  -沃克探员呢
- When it went up. - And agent Walker?
我不知道
I don't know.
蕾妮  这是杰克
Renee,this is Jack.
收到请回答
Do you copy?
蕾妮  这是杰克
Renee,this is Jack.
收到请回答
Do you copy?
该死
Damn it.
阿尔梅达
Almeida.
毒气罐还在吧
You got the canister?
是的
Yeah.
我看看
Let me see.
快点  我们要快点离开
Hurry up,we need to get moving.
走
Let's go.
蕾妮
Renee!
Renee...
-蕾妮  -杰克
- Renee! - Jack.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-我没事  -他没呼吸了
- Yeah,- But he's not breathing.
医生
We need a medic!
让他们来照料他  你快跟我出去
They've got him. I want to get you out of here.
快点  我们走
Come on,let's go now.
你怎么知道这是个陷阱的
How'd you know it was a trap?
斯托勒的发射器在建筑物外面
Stoller's transponder was outside of the building.
他们想削弱我们封锁线  找突破口
They were trying to thin our ranks,create a diversion.
封锁出现漏洞了没
Has the cordon been breached?
没  我告诉他们原地待命
No,I told the men to maintain their positions.
封锁线安全
The perimeter's secure.
杰克  他们好像知道我们的计划
It's almost like they knew,Jack.
他们在楼内布置炸药
They would have needed time
总要花时间的
To wire this building with explosives.
这是我们计划搜索的最后一个据点
This was the last sector we were due to search.
-你认为他们知道我们的搜索顺序吗  -肯定的
- You think they knew your sweep patterns? - They must have.
上帝啊
Oh,my god.
杰克  怎么了
Jack,what is it?
回头在你车那边见
I'll meet you back at your vehicle.
要我帮你忙吗
Hey,you want me to take him?
不用  我可以的
No,I got him.
里面需要你的帮助
They need your help inside.
米泽尔探员
Agent Mizelli.
我是鲍尔  你刚才说到
This is Bauer. you said you wanted to talk to me
托尼供的嫌犯文森特·卡蒂夫
About tony's suspect vincent cardiff.
对  你终于回话给我了
Yes,yes,thanks for getting back to me.
听着  你告诉我说他
Listen,uh,you told me that he expired
在托尼·阿尔梅达的审讯中死了
During the course of tony Almeida's interrogation.
对  托尼就是这么跟我说的
Yeah,that's what tony told me.
不可能是他
Well,it can't be him.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
一小时前文森特·卡蒂夫
Vincent cardiff was picked up
试图偷渡去加拿大
Over an hour ago by customs,
的时候被海关逮捕
Trying to cross the border into Canada.
确定吗
Are you sure?
很肯定  我现在拿着他的逮捕报告
Look,I'm positive,I've got his arrest report right here.
卡蒂夫还活着
Cardiff's alive.
他身上有没有
Were there any signs
被审讯的迹象
From his interrogation
暴力威胁  虐待  有吗
Physical violence, abuse,anything at all?
报告上面没写
Nothing's indicated on the report.
所以我问你是否
That's why I was asking if maybe
有可能把托尼告诉你的名字说错了
You had mistaken the name almeida gave you.
接着
Here you go.
谢谢
Thanks.
托尼
Tony!
什么
Yeah.
我需要和你谈谈
We need to talk.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我今天早些时候告诉过你
I told you earlier today,
如果你对我撒谎  我会亲自把你杀了
If you were lying to me I'd kill you myself.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
卡蒂夫  文森特·卡蒂夫
Cardiff,vincent cardiff--
你说他在审讯期间死了
You said he was killed during his interrogation.
是啊  怎么了
Yeah,so?
他好端端的活着  被逮捕了
He's alive and well,in custody,
根本没有曾被虐待的迹象
And he's showing no signs of physical abuse.
解释下
Explain that.
好吧  听着  杰克  抱歉
All right,look, Jack,I'm sorry.
卡蒂夫知道一但他泄露了情报
Cardiff knew that by spilling that intel,
肯定会活不成
He was going to get himself killed,
我说我可以让调查局认为
I told him i'd let the FBI think
他已经死了  让他可以逃匿
He was dead,so he could walk away and disappear.
我认为那是无关紧要的谎话
I thought it was just a meaningless lie.
你和我干这行那么多年早应该知道
You and I have been doing this long enough to know
根本就没有谎话是无关紧要的
That there is no such thing as a meaningless lie.
你在其中扮演什么角色
How are you involved in this?
杰克  你这样说没有道理
You're not making any sense,Jack.
那情报是对的
That intel was good.
没那情报你进不了白宫
Without it you'd have never been in the white house
救不了总统
To save the president.
你到底扮演什么角色
What is your involvement?!
你头脑不清醒了
You're not thinking straight.
你是怎么中枪的
How were you shot?
是卡维斯真的还有同伙
Does galvez even have a second man...
还是那个同伙就是你
Or was it just you?
住嘴  听下你刚才说的
Just stop and listen to what you're saying.
这是扯淡  精神错乱
It's insane. It's paranoia.
快把枪放下吧
Now,why don't you put the gun down?
别动
Don't you move!
毒素在影响你的判断能力
The toxin is starting to affect your judgment.
你知道的  不是吗
That's what's happening. you can see that,right?
这就是你要找的东西对吧
Is this what you're looking for?
我不想伤害你  杰克
I never wanted to hurt you,Jack.
我告诉过你别管这事
I told you to stay out of it.
但你就是不听  是吧
But you wouldn't listen, would you?
我需要帮助  他开始抽搐了
Can we get some help here? this man's having a seizure.
请后退
Stand back,please.
去拿下我的包  给梅塞尔医生打电话
Go get my bag and call Dr. Mason.
我没看到伤口
I don't see anything.
伤口肯定在背部
The wound must be posterior.
长官  我需要你翻个身
Sir,I need to turn you on your side.
放下对讲机  开你的车
Put it down and keep driving. now!